<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>overflow:auto</title>
 <link href="http://demersdesigns.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://demersdesigns.com/"/>
 <updated>2016-01-03T15:16:24-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://demersdesigns.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Mark Otto</name>
   <email>markdotto@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Adding a Local Project to Github</title>
   <link href="http://demersdesigns.com/2016/01/03/add-new-project-to-github/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://demersdesigns.com/2016/01/03/add-new-project-to-github</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things that I do on the web just infrequently enough to not be able to commit to memory. One of those things happens to be adding a brand new local project to GitHub. The process is the same every time. I try to remember, I head to Google, I land on &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/adding-an-existing-project-to-github-using-the-command-line/&quot;&gt;this handy page&lt;/a&gt; that outlines all of the steps and I type them in one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, looking this up every time is a waste of time, but committing it to memory is difficult if you aren’t doing it all the time. I decided to create a quick little function to include in my &lt;code&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; that automates the process. The only requirement is to pass in the address for the new repo on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the snippet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function &lt;/span&gt;git-new&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  git init;
  git add .;
  git commit -m &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Initial commit&quot;&lt;/span&gt;;
  git remote add origin &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;;
  git remote -v;
  git push origin master;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this has been added to your &lt;code&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt;, you just need to run &lt;code&gt;source ~/.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt;. Now, you can navigate to the folder containing the new project you want to add to GitHub and type the following:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git-new git@github.com:YOUR-USERNAME/YOUR-PROJECT.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Accessing localhost on a VirtualBox VM</title>
   <link href="http://demersdesigns.com/2016/01/02/localhost-on-virtualbox-vm/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://demersdesigns.com/2016/01/02/localhost-on-virtualbox-vm</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are a number of great ways to test your web projects against the growing number of browsers and mobile devices. Lately, I have found myself using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.browserstack.com/&quot;&gt;BrowserStack&lt;/a&gt;. It’s reasonably priced, easy to use, and has a large range of browsers and devices available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for Internet Explorer testing, I find myself going back to the virtual machines that are provided by the team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.windows.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/tools/vms/mac/&quot;&gt;Modern.ie&lt;/a&gt;. They take a little bit of time to download and get installed, but the fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xdissent/ievms&quot;&gt;ievms&lt;/a&gt; project makes the download and setup super simple if you are handy with the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that trips me up once I get the environment set up, is how to actually look at my local site in the IE browser that I have loaded in the virtual environment. Unfortunately, it isn’t as simple as just typing in &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:3000&lt;/code&gt; or using your local machine’s IP address. To view a site running on localhost, you can simply use &lt;code&gt;http://10.0.2.2:3000&lt;/code&gt; and that will map back to localhost on your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am mainly writing this down because it trips me up every time. Hopefully, it saves other people time and frustration as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
